Mahendra Pratap Singh Ahada

Ahada.mahendra@gmail.com

+91 9413195506

Objective

To work hard with full dedication for the achievement of organization objectives under satisfying job contact, hence enhancing my skills and knowledge and ready to learn new things.

Summary

My main area of experience has been in the field of Web Application And Mobile App Development . Developed the User Interactive web pages in a professional manner using web technologies like Bootstrap, Html5, Css3, and then Writing Services and Reusable Component and integrating it to templates using Angular 10 as per company's standards. Also I am working on Flutter from the beginning of 2019 and have built some apps like chat app, location finder app, ecommerce app, meal app and an expanse manager.

Skills & Competencies

• App Technologies: Flutter, Dart, Firebase.

• Scripting Language: JavaScript, ES6

• Frameworks: Angular 2,4,8,10.

• Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Iquery, Bootstrap, Materialize

• **Knowledge**: Git, Jira, FreshDesk Adobe Photoshop

Education

Year	Degree	Institutional Name	Percentage
2015	Bachelor of Technology (CSE)	Arya college of Engineering & IT, Kukas, Jaipur	62.92
	RTU, Kota		
2011	Class 12 th RBSE, Ajmer	Government Senior Secondary School, Lohariya,Banswara	73.38
2009	Class 10 th RBSE, Ajmer	Government Senior Secondary School, Lohariya,Banswara	70.67

Experience

· Flutter Developer

Self Learner [Jan-2019 - Current]

My learnings are:-

- · Running apps on different devices & debugging apps, widgets, styling, responsive & adaptive, user interfaces and apps, navigation.
- · state management using providers ,sending http requests,user authentication,animations.
- · Using native device features (Camera, Maps, Location), firebase, image upload, push notifications.
- · Deploying an android and ios app to store.
- · Built apps like chat app, location finder app, ecommerce app, meal app and an expanse manager.
- · Technologies: Flutter, Firebase, Dart.

· Software Engineer

The Scalers, Bengaluru[March-2020 - Current]

My roles and responsibilities in the company includes following parts:-

- · As a Senior Engineer I am working on building various retail applications for our client using the latest version of angular.
- · I actively contribute to the development and release.
- · I also take care of DevOps tasks like using teamcity for continuous integration, Git tagging and uploading artifacts to Nexus repository.
- · Followed agile & scrum methodology for the development of the product.
- Technologies: Angular 8,9,10, HTML5,CSS3,Javascript, Bootstrap,ES6

· Sr. Software Engineer

BuildSupply, Gurgaon [Dec-2017 - Feb-2020(2.3Yrs)]

My roles and responsibilities in the company includes following parts:-

- · Participates in Sprint Planning, Tasking and Estimation of the assigned work.
- · Responsible for the development of reusable components, services and user interfaces and code reviews.
- · Used Angular and bootstrap for developing single page web application's internal reusable components.
- · Cooperating with the back-end developer in the process of building the RESTful API.
- · Followed agile & scrum methodology for the development of the product.
- · Technologies: Angular 4,8, HTML5,CSS3,Javascript, Bootstrap,ES6

· UI Developer

BigAppCompany, Bengaluru[Aug-2016 - Dec-2017(1.4 Yrs)]

My roles and responsibilities in the company includes following parts:-

- · Research about latest Web Application trends update it to the designer team , Development of the web application as per the PSD Design, Writing Services and Reusable Component and integrating it to template.
- · Coordination with clients, understanding their requirements and taking feedback as well.
- · Provide support to the companies in house product Spotsoon.
- · Technologies: Angular 2,4, HTML5,CSS3,Javascript, Bootstrap

· UI Developer

Webbazaar, Bengaluru[Oct-2015 - Jul 2016 (8 Month)]

My roles and responsibilities in the company includes following parts:-

- · Designed and developed the entire website for Clients.
- · Maintained active conversation with the client to ensure the site met his needs.
- · Researched industry trends and websites to provide top quality design.
- · Technologies: HTML5,CSS3,Javascript, Bootstrap,Jquery,Bootstrap

Projects

· NPCI [National Payments Corporation of India] (Web Application)

· Description – National Payments Corporation of India (NPCI) is an umbrella organization for all retail payments systems in India. Here our job is to develop internal portals for certification of NPCI which are going to be accessed by all the banks of India. Here we have developed portals for Superadmin, Banks, Business Development Team, Customer Support Team and C-Flow Team.

My work is to take care of all the Front end development of all the portals.

DIGVERVE (Web Application)

· Description - Fully responsive web application which provides a platform for educational institutes to upgrade their pedagogy and teacher – student interaction. This one is the student panel where they can check all the questions and answer from their respective class, assignments from teacher, they can ask private questions to any teacher in any departments, updates about news and events and many more

Achievements

- Event Manager of 'Techno-Mystify' in Exergies, 2014 held at Arya College of Engineering and IT.
- Winner of 'MusicMenia' in 'SHRADHANJALI-12' held at Arya College of Engineering and IT.
- Cricket team **captain** for consecutive four year.

Personal Details

Date of birth : February 25, 1995Languages : English, Hindi

Gender : Male Nationality : Indian

• Interest : Blog reading, and Surfing internet.

• Address : Electronics city, Bengaluru.

Declaration

Hereby declare that all the above furnished information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief. The originals will be produced as required.

Date (MAHENDRA PRATAP SINGH AHADA)

Place: Bengaluru